准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
神秘的盒子
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
派大星
Patrick?
Oh, Patrick
准备好去捉水母了吗
Are you ready to go jelly fishing?
天啊  那还用问
Oh, boy, am I
网给你
Here's your net
快点啊  派大星
Well, come on, Patrick
水母可不会自己捉自己的
The jellyfish don't catch themselves
我得先收好我的秘密盒
First, I have to put away my secret box
秘密盒
Secret box?
你没跟我说过你有
You never told me about your
秘密盒啊
secret box
住手  偷窥狂宝宝
Hands off, Peeping Bob
这秘密盒可是我专属的
This here's my secret box
并且要是我给你看了里面的东西
Besides, if I showed you what was inside
就不能算秘密了
it wouldn't be a secret anymore
废话
Duh
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
要是你能看到我秘密盒里的东西
If only you could see inside my secret box
你的一生都将会改变
it would change your life
没事的  派大星
It's okay, Patrick
我对秘密了如指掌
I know all about secrets
真知道
You do?
我有超多的秘密
I've got a gazillion secrets
比如什么
Like what?
众所周知秘密最好的一点
Well, it's no secret that the best thing about a secret
就是秘密地把自己的秘密告诉别人
is secretly telling someone your secret
从而秘密地再把一个秘密
thereby secretly adding another secret
收藏到秘密的秘密收藏里去
to their secret collection of secrets
可秘密了
secretly
你要听我一个秘密吗
You want to hear one of my secrets?
那还用问
Do I?
我想想
Let's see
你知道你是我最好的朋友吗
Did you know you're my best friend?
不会
No
吧
way
再来听一个
Let's hear another one
好啊
Okay
悄悄讲  我有点幼稚
Secretly, I'm a little bit naive
我对你大为改观了  海绵宝宝
l'll never look at you the same way again, SpongeBob
天啊
Gosh
再跟我讲点秘密
Tell me some more secrets
好吧
Okay
我爱我在蟹堡王的工作
l love my job at The Krusty Krab
我睡觉都穿鞋
I sleep with my shoes on
我喜欢面包两面都涂果酱
l like jelly on both sides of my toast
我有本借书逾期了
l've got an overdue library book
我觉得捉水母跟吹泡泡就是
l think jelly fishing and bubble blowing are the
我上班从没迟到
I've never been late for work
我跟人讲话说过花哨两字
I've said the word "fancy" in conversation
我喜欢听装卸区公告跳舞
l like to dance to loading zone announcements
我还没有拿到驾照
l still don't have my driver's license
我有点太矮了
l'm a little on the short side
我现在就穿着三条内裤
and I'm wearing three pairs of underwear right now
哇
Gasp
我猜都猜不到
I never would have guessed
能给我看你秘密盒里的东西了吗
Now, will you show me what's inside your secret box?
不给  海绵宝宝
No, SpongeBob
只有我才能知道  不能让你知道
lt's for me to know, and for you to never find out
也许你是能一眼被看穿  海绵宝宝
You may be an open book, SpongeBob
但是我可比你那情况更复杂
but I'm a bit more complicated than that
我内心深不可测的城府可神秘了
The inner machinations of my mind are an enigma
牛奶
是吗
Oh, yeah?
我倒也有不少秘密玩意
Well, I got plenty of secret stuff, too
我穿了秘密袜子
I've got my secret socks on
小蜗
还有秘密小蜗食盆
And my secret Gary's bowl
秘密电视
My secret TV
还有秘密电视频道
and my secret TV channel
你觉得怎么样呢  派大星
What do you think of that, Patrick?
派大星
Patrick?
要是里面的东西让你给看到了
Maybe if you saw what was inside
就会知道它为什么就得是秘密了
you'd know why it has to be secret
在这特别的盒子里
Inside this very box
是整个秘密国度中最秘密的秘密
is the most secrety secret in all of Secretdom
而我正是它唯一的见证者
and I am its sole witness
这就是个重担  海绵宝宝
It's a heavy burden, SpongeBob
但是谁都不能知道这盒子的神秘之处
but nobody must know the mystery of the box
谁都不能
Nobody
连
Not even
章鱼哥家都不能知道
Squidward's house
一刻都不能停
It's a full-time job
我要时刻保持警惕
I'm constantly on the alert
不知道会有谁会突然要
You never know when someone's gonna
海绵宝宝  你这是想干什么
SpongeBob, what do you think you're doing?
那是我的秘密盒
That's my secret box
给我交出来
Now hand it over
可是派大星  我必须得知道秘密
But, Patrick, I must know the secret
跟你讲最后一遍  海绵宝宝
For the last time, SpongeBob
不准
no
拜托  就一眼
Come on, just a peek
不行
Never
既然到这种地步了
So, it's come to this
亏我们还加了永远好朋友俱乐部
And to think we joined the Best Friends Forever Club
听着  偷秘密宝宝
Listen up, SpongeBob "Secret Stealer" Pants
要是你再来靠近我的秘密盒
If you ever come near my secret box again
我们就绝交
we won't be friends anymore
可
But
我们应该是
we're supposed to be
永远好朋友的
friends forever
海绵宝宝                    派大星
我内心好龌龊
I feel so filthy
我玷污了我们的友谊园林
I have soiled our friendship garden
我就只是忍不住而已
I just couldn't help myself
我知道那是你的秘密
I know it's your secret
我保证会尊重的
I promise to respect that
求你原谅我吧  派大星
Please forgive me, Patrick
求你了
please
那
Well
也不能全怪你吧
I guess it's not all your fault
毕竟这可是个特别棒的秘密
After all, this is a pretty great secret
一般人完全抗拒不了最棒的秘密
I mean, how could you resist the greatest secret ever?
最神奇
The most amazing
最神秘
mysterious
最强大的秘密  裤头村独有
powerful secret in all of Bikini Bottom?
那你怎么说  兄弟
So, what do you say, buddy?
还是朋友吗
Friends?
朋友
Friends
那个盒子里有什么东西
What could be in that box
派大星居然还不让我开盒看看
that Patrick doesn't want me to see?
可能是全世界唯一一只白化水母
Maybe it's the world's only albino jellyfish
还可能派大星是个珠宝大盗
or maybe Patrick's a master jewel thief
盒里满是钻石
and it's full of diamonds
还可能派大星是个发神经的疯子
Or maybe Patrick's a deranged maniac
会把受害人的断头装进盒子里
who keeps his victims' severed heads in a box
或者更糟
Or even worse
可能是我圣诞节派对时的丑照
maybe it's an embarrassing snapshot of me
from a Christmas party
一定要知道秘密盒里有什么东西
l got to find out what's in that secret box
不知道就不睡
I'm not going to rest till I do
有了
That's it
要怎么看秘密盒里的东西呢
How do you look into a secret box?
当然是要秘密地看
Secretly, of course
我只要在派大星睡着的时候拿走盒子
I'll just take the box while Patrick's sleeping
往盒子里面看
look inside
趁派大星没来得及注意
and before Patrick even has time to notice
偷偷溜回去还
I'll slide it back
派大星就发现不了
Patrick won't know
而我自己又多了一份秘密
and I'll have my own little secret
是不是好办法啊  小蜗
Good idea, eh, Gary?
不
No
你懂个什么啊
What do you know?
你就一蜗牛
You're a snail
磨来磨去
Snizzlefrazzy
是谁
Who's it?
秘密
Se-e-ecret
我得再安静点
I got to be more quiet
可不能让派大星醒过来
I don't want to wake Patrick up
谁在那
Who's there?
谁
Who's
薯片
水
Water
秘密盒子啊
Good old secret box
看看里面有什么东西吧
Let's see what's inside
晚安了  小盒盒
Nighty-night, boxie
派大星还真睡得挺沉的
Gee, Patrick sure is a heavy sleeper
谁说的话
Who said that?
是谁
Who's there?
是蛤蜊神偷
It's the clam burglar
还在偷我的秘密盒
And he's stealing my secret box
快给我交出来  秘密盒抢匪
Hand over the goods, secret-box bandit
准备迎接你一生中最难受的枕头大战
and prepare for the most unpleasant
pillow fight of your life
等一下  派大星
Wait, wait, wait, Patrick
住手
Stop
是我  海绵宝宝
It's me, SpongeBob
少来了  大盗
Nice try, burglar
海绵宝宝是我最好的朋友
But SpongeBob's my best friend
他从来就不会偷我东西
and he'd never steal from me
不对
No
真的是我  派大星
Really, Patrick
看
Look
这是永远好朋友
It's the Best Friends Forever
永远好朋友戒指
Best Friends Forever Ring
友情戒指
Our friendship ring
真的是你
It is you
你怎么能这样
How could you do this?
希望我这么说能让你好受些
If it makes you feel any better
我没看里面的东西
I haven't looked inside
够了  海绵宝宝
That's it, SpongeBob
你已经越过底线了
You have crossed the line
现在  这份友情结束了
As of right now, this friendship is over
真的吗
Really?
假的  真的想看你就看吧
Nah, you can look inside if you really want to
好啊
Okay
这是我一生中最激动的时刻之一了
This is one of the most exciting moments of my life
我要开盒了
Well, here it goes
怎么样
Well?
我不是跟你说过吗
Didn't I tell you?
是不是很棒
Isn't it great?
就一根线头
It's just a string
秘密线头
A secret string
那没事了  你说是就是吧
Boy, when you're right, you're right
你秘密盒里就那玩意啊
That's some secret box you got there
好吧
Yeah
谢谢你给我看
Thanks for showing me that
晚安  派大星
Well, good night, Patrick
明天见
See you tomorrow
晚安  海绵宝宝
Good night, SpongeBob
我早该知道的
I should have known
一直都只是根线头而已
it was just a piece of string all along
我等不及要跟小蜗讲了
Wait till I tell Gary
幸好他没有把秘密线头拉起来
Good thing he didn't pull the secret string
打开我秘密盒里的秘密夹层
opening the secret compartment of my secret box
让海绵宝宝圣诞派对的丑照给露出来
revealing one embarrassing snapshot
of SpongeBob at that Christmas party
圣诞快乐  海绵宝宝
Merry Christmas, SpongeBob
怪才乐队
导演
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
那个
Yeah, uh
我们是街边那家宠物医院的
we're with the pet hospital down the street
听说你家里有只动物快要死了
and I understand
you have a dying animal on the premises
喂
Hello
你正在向被忽略的天才家里通话
You've reached The House of Unrecognized Talent
请听到声音后留言
Please start after the
听着好像你得处理一只快死了的动物
Sounds as though you've got a dying animal to attend to
对吧  老朋友
eh, old chum?
音乐班的章鱼威廉花花公子
Squilliam Fancyson from band class?
听说你现在在耍收银机
I hear you're playing the cash register now
有时会吧
Well, sometimes
你一字眉怎么样
How's the unibrow?
可大可值钱了
It's big and valuable
我现在是个豪华大乐队的指挥
l'm the leader of a big fancy band now
下周就要到泡泡碗去演出了
and we're supposed to play the Bubble Bowl next week
泡泡泡
The Bu-Bu-Bu
没错
That's right
你的梦想生活被我抢了  章鱼哥
I'm living your dreams, Squidward
问题就在于我下周没空  来不了
The problem is, I'm busy next week and can't make it
所以我希望你跟你乐队能帮忙替一下
So, I was hoping you and your band could cover for us
我  我我我
I-I-I-I'd, uh
我就知道
I knew it
你连个乐队都没有
You don't even have a band
好吧  不打扰你继续当服务生了
Well, I'll just let you get back
to the service industry now
等下
Hold it
我碰巧已经不卖快餐了
It just so happens that I don't sell fast food
我确实有个乐队
I do have a band
泡泡碗的演出我们可是去定了
and we're gonna play that Bubble Bowl
怎么样啊  花花小子
How do you like that, Fancyboy?
下周二祝你好运
Good luck next Tuesday
希望观众都带足了布洛芬
I hope the audience brings lots of ibuprofen
我得赶紧招个游行乐队来
l've got to drum up a marching band fast
鼓
招
Drum
乐队笑话
Band humor
快看这个
想要充实你的枯燥生活吗
"Looking to add fulfillment to your dull, dull life?"
那就加入最棒的音乐明星团
"Then become part of the greatest musical sensation
轰动裤头村吧
ever to hit Bikini Bottom"
烘培坊
被成千上万的陌生人永远崇拜
"And be forever adored
by thousands of people you don't know"
更不必说免费小点心了
"Not to mention free refreshments"
今晚开始练习  八点半准时到达
"Practice begins tonight, 8:30 sharp"
笨蛋乐器出租员害我迟到了
Stupid music rental clerk made me late
那古板三叶虫连双簧管跟手肘都不分
That trilobite didn't know an oboe from an elbow
[ oboe（双簧管）与 elbow（手肘）谐音 ]
手肘
Elbow
又是乐队笑话
More band humor
各位  各位
People, people
都安静
Settle down
好了
Okay, now
你们有多少先前耍过乐器的
How many of you
have played musical instruments before?
刑具算不算
Do instruments of torture count?
不算
No
蛋黄酱算乐器吗
Is mayonnaise an instrument?
不算  派大星
No, Patrick
蛋黄酱不算乐器
mayonnaise is not an instrument
辣根酱也不算乐器
Horseradish is not an instrument either
那好吧  没人有经验
That's fine, no one has any experience
幸好我天赋异禀  足够教你们了
Fortunately, I have enough talent for all of you
教你们
All of you
什么时候领免费小点心
When do we get the free food?
好了  跟着我吹
Okay, try to repeat after me
铜管乐器组  起
Brass section, go
好
Good
木管乐器组
Now the wind
再来鼓
And the drums
真可惜没杀死我
Too bad that didn't kill me
我们来试试跟上节奏
Let's just try stepping in rhythm
现在我要大家站成五人一排
Now, I want everyone to stand in straight rows of five
我们是不是要开始踢腿了
ls this the part where we start kicking?
不对  海绵宝宝
No, SpongeBob
歌舞队才那样
that's a chorus line
踢腿
Kicking?
我要踢腿
I want to do some kicking
你可恶
Why, you
我非得
Why, I ought to
开白色轿车的那位
Whoever's the owner of the white sedan
你忘记关车灯了
you left your lights on
第二天
好的各位  非常完美
Okay, that's perfect, everybody
泡泡碗  我们来了
Bubble Bowl, here we come
旗手  把旗子舞好
Flag twirlers, really spin those things
好  转弯
Okay, turn
旗手  快上
Flag twirlers, let's go
我要看你们舞好旗子
I want to see some spinning
旗手  舞起来
Flag twirlers, let's move
快点
Come on
舞
Move
第三天
口琴独奏怎么样了  痞老板
How's that harmonica solo coming, Plankton?
大有可为啊
It's tremendous
要看下吗
You want to see?
第四天
这是我们演出前集合的最后一夜
Well, this is our last night together before the show
虽然你们打一开始就毫无长进
And I know that you haven't improved since we began
不过我有个理论
But I have a theory
人们想表现聪明就会大声说话  对吧
People talk loud when they want to act smart, right?
对
Correct
所以要是我们演奏声音大
So if we play loud
别人就可能会觉得我们水平高
people might think we're good
大家准备好了吗
Everybody ready?
一  二
And a-one and a-two
一二三四
and a-one, two, three, four
好吧  新理论
Okay, new theory
我们可能该演奏得非常小声
Maybe we should play so quietly
小到听不见
no one can hear us
也许要想演奏得不那么难听
Well, maybe we wouldn't sound so bad
某些人就不应该瞎耍大肉钳
if some people didn't try to play with big, meaty claws
你刚在说什么  混账
What did you say, punk?
大
Big
肉
meaty
钳
claws
这大肉钳可不单单是用来求偶的
Well, these claws ain't for just attracting mates
放马过来  老头子
Bring it on, old man
放马过来
Bring it on
别这样  各位
No, people
都明智点  别冲动
Let's be smart and bring it off
现在连会说话的奶酪都要来训我们了
So now the talking cheese is going to preach to us
住手  住手
Wait, wait
我知道局势很紧张
I know tensions are high
看招
Take that
乐器交了押金的  各位
There's a deposit on that equipment, people
请你们静一静
Settle down, please
打他
Hit him
下课了
Class is over
好吧  明天见
Okay, yeah, see ya tomorrow
真不错
That was good
下课后你要干嘛
Say, what are you doing after
你们成功了
Well, you did it
你们夺走了我奔向快乐的机会
You took my one chance at happiness
也粉碎了这个机会
and crushed it
粉碎成一片片细小微小极小的碎片
Crushed it into little, tiny, bite-size pieces
我真的对你们寄予了更高的期望
I really had expected better of you people
看来我连期望都失败了吧
I guess I'm a loser for that, too
明天不用麻烦你们过来了
Don't bother showing up tomorrow
就跟主办方说你们排练出事故死掉了
I'll just tell them you all died in a marching accident
谢谢大家
So, thanks
谢谢你们一事无成
Thanks for nothing
不客气
You're welcome
我们到底是什么样的怪物
What kind of monsters are we?
那个可怜人在有需要时向我们求助
That poor creature came to us in his hour of need
可我们却让他失望了
and we failed him
章鱼哥方便时总会出手相助
Squidward's always been there for us
when it was convenient for him
埃芙琳  你家小吉米困在火场的时候
Evelyn, when your little Jimmy was trapped in a fire
是谁救了他
who rescued him?
消防员
A fireman
拉里
And, Larry
你因为美黑药而心脏骤停的时候
when your heart gave out from all those tanning pills
是谁救活了你
who revived you?
救护车上的人
Some guy in an ambulance
对
Right
那如果我们都假装章鱼哥是消防员
So, if we all could just pretend
that Squidward was a fireman
或者救护车上的人
or some guy in an ambulance
那么大家一定就能够团结起来
then I'm sure we could all pull together
找出加入乐队的真正意义
and discover what it truly means
to be in a marching band
对  为了消防员
Yeah, for the fireman
对
Yeah
让章鱼哥抬起头来吧
Now let's make Squidward proud
一  二
A-one, a-two
一起开始吧
a squiddly-diddly do
泡泡碗
我就知道会这样子
I knew this was going to happen
主办方非得另外再找个乐队不可
They're just going to have to find another band to play
乐队入口
我就只希望
I just hope that
章鱼威廉没有发现
Squilliam doesn't find out
章鱼威廉
Squilliam
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我就只是要看你出丑而已
I just wanted to watch you blow it
那么  你乐队在哪里啊
So, where's your band?
他们来不了了
They couldn't come
他们
They
死了
died
那这又是谁
Then who's that?
是我的乐队
That would be my band
我们准备好表演了  章鱼哥
We're ready to perform, Squidward
章鱼哥
Well, Squiddy
你乐队在我心目中刚好就这模样
this is exactly how I pictured your band would look
那是人家的热切表情
That's his eager face
这应该是我最后一次在这镇上露面了
I guess this will be the last time
I can show my face in this town
这就对了  章鱼哥
That's the spirit, Squidward
好了  球迷们
Okay, football fans
掌声有请裤头村超级乐队
put your hands together
for the Bikini Bottom Super Band
这些鱼长得可真是丑
These are some ugly-looking fish
可能我们在一家有毒的垃圾场附近
Maybe we're near one of those toxic-waste dumps
我觉得我要吐了
I think I'm going to be sick
好了  各位
Okay, everybody
结束这一切吧
Let's get this over with
一
One
二
two
三
three
四
four
胜者获一切
The winner takes all
正是追击的快感
It's the thrill of one more kill
屹立到最后的人
The last one to fall
决不会灰心丧志
Will never sacrifice their will
不要回头看  那逼近的世界
Don't ever look back on the world closing in
不懈地战斗  在风中展翅
Be on the attack with your wings on the wind
比赛即将开始
Oh, the games will begin
这是甜蜜  甜蜜的胜利
And it's sweet, sweet, sweet victory, yeah
任由我们去争取
And it's ours for the taking
由我们奋斗
It's ours for the fight
这甜蜜  甜蜜的胜利
And the sweet, sweet, sweet victory, yeah
终有人屹立到最后
And the one who's last to fall
甜蜜的胜利
Sweet, sweet, sweet victory